Inventory of the Ginetta Sagan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Amnesty International, 1974-1987
  - Tucker, David, 1983 (Box-folder 122: 9)
  - Ideas for speeches, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 122: 10)
  - Membership expenditures, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 122: 11)
  - Urgent Action, 1984 (Box-folder 122: 12)
  - Correspondence and printed matter, 1984 (Box-folder 122: 13)
  - Internal documents, correspondence, and clippings, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 122: 14)
    Includes compact sound cassette of song "Beyond War" by Joe Fisher
  - Addresses and contacts, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 1-3)
  - Group 19 internal documents, correspondence, and clippings, 1981 (Box-folder 123: 4)
  - Correspondence, internal documents, and annual general meeting materials, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 124: 1-3)
  - Medical committee, 1975 (Box-folder 124: 4)
  - Concert, 1977 (Box-folder 124: 5)
  - Philippines, 1981 (Box-folder 124: 6)
  - Morocco, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 7)
  - Internal documents, 1983 (Box-folder 124: 8)
  - Council of the Americas meeting, 1984 (Box-folder 124: 9)
    Includes letter from Flora Lewis
  - International Secretariat internal documents, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 1)
  - Board meeting, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 2)
  - Campaign for membership, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 4)
  - Ed Meese correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 5)
  - Medical committee, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 125: 6)
  - Nazi war criminals, 1981 (Box-folder 125: 7)
  - Cambodia, 1983 (Box-folder 125: 8)
  - Hawaii prospects, 1976-1982 and undated (Box-folder 125: 9)
    Includes magnetic typewriter card
  - Labor News, 1984 (Box-folder 125: 10)
  - Internal documents, 1983 (Box-folder 125: 11-12)
  - Campaign Against Torture printed matter, undated (Box-folder 125: 13)
  - GS notes, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 126: 1)
  - Paris Conference for the Abolition of Torture, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 126: 2)
  - GS notes and internal documents, 1973-1974 and undated (Box-folder 126: 3)
  - Annual general meeting, 1983 (Box-folder 126: 4)
  - Internal documents and clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 126: 5)
  - Heritage Foundation, 1983 (Box-folder 126: 6)
  - Fundraising, 1976, 1983 (Box-folder 126: 7)
  - Amnesty Action, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 126: 8)
  - Mailing lists, 1983 (Box-folder 126: 9)
  - Addresses, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 127: 1)
  - Photograph of GS from Western Regional Conference, 1986 (Box-folder 127: 2)
  - Annual reports, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 127: 3)
  - Bulletin, 1985 (Box-folder 127: 4)
  - Clippings, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 127: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 128: 1)
  - Matchbox, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 128: 2-4)
  - Amnesty Action, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 128: 5)
  - Fundraising, undated (Box-folder 128: 6)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986
    - A (Box-folder 129: 1)
    - B (Box-folder 129: 2)
    - C (Box-folder 129: 3)
    - D (Box-folder 129: 4)
    - E (Box-folder 130: 1)
    - F (Box-folder 130: 2)
    - G (Box-folder 130: 3)
    - H (Box-folder 130: 4)
    - I-K (Box-folder 130: 5)
    - L (Box-folder 130: 6)
    - M-N (Box-folder 130: 7)
    - O-Q (Box-folder 130: 8)
    - R (Box-folder 130: 9)
    - S (Box-folder 131: 1)
    - U (Box-folder 131: 2)
    - W (Box-folder 131: 3)
    - X-Z (Box-folder 131: 4)
  - Argentina, 1983 (Box-folder 131: 5)
  - Philippines, 1981 and 1985 (Box-folder 132: 1)
  - Romania, 1978 (Box-folder 132: 2)
  - South Africa, 1985 (Box-folder 132: 3)
  - South Korea, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 132: 4)
  - Soviet musicians, 1985 (Box-folder 132: 5)
  - Soviet Union, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 132: 6)
  - Sri Lanka, 1983 (Box-folder 132: 7)
  - Syria, 1983 (Box-folder 132: 8)
  - Thailand, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 132: 9)
  - Turkey, 1985 (Box-folder 132: 10)
  - Uganda, 1985 (Box-folder 132: 11)
  - Uruguay, 1984 (Box-folder 132: 12-13)
  - Yugoslavia, 1982 (Box-folder 132: 14)
  - Zaire, 1985 (Box-folder 132: 15)
  - Zimbabwe, undated (Box-folder 132: 16)
  - El Salvador, 1982 (Box-folder 133: 1)
  - Iraq, 1983 (Box-folder 133: 2)
  - Israel, 1979 (Box-folder 133: 3)
  - Israel and Lebanon, 1982 (Box-folder 133: 4)
  - Jamaica, 1984 (Box-folder 133: 5)
  - Kenya, 1982 (Box-folder 133: 6)
  - Korea, 1981 (Box-folder 133: 7)
  - Laos, 1985 (Box-folder 133: 8)
  - Liberia, undated (Box-folder 133: 9)
  - Morocco, 1981 (Box-folder 133: 10)
  - Mozambique, 1981 (Box-folder 133: 11)
  - Niger, 1983 (Box-folder 133: 12)
  - Paraguay, 1984 (Box-folder 133: 13)
  - Peru, 1985 (Box-folder 133: 14)
  - Urgent Action, 1986 (Box-folder 133: 15-22)
  - 25th anniversary, 1985 (Box-folder 134: 1)
  - Iran, 1976-1986 (Box-folder 134: 2)
  - Reader's Digest article on GS, 1985 April (Box-folder 134: 3)
  - Indonesia, 1986 (Box-folder 134: 4)
  - Addresses, 1985 (Box-folder 134: 5-6)
  - Clippings and notes, 1984 (Box-folder 134: 7)
  - Psychiatric abuses and activities, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 134: 8)
  - The Festival of Forbidden Film, 1984 (Box-folder 134: 9)
  - Guatemala, 1985 (Box-folder 134: 10)
  - Stuart Sagan writing on Vietnam, 1985 (Box-folder 134: 11)
  - Terrorism, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 135: 1)
  - Personal correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 135: 2)
  - Calendar, 1984 (Box-folder 135: 3)
  - Invitations, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 135: 4)
  - Amnesty International annual report, 1985 (Box-folder 135: 5)
  - Notes and correspondence by GS, 1984 (Box-folder 135: 6)
  - Amnesty International correspondence and printed matter, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 135: 7)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1984 (Box-folder 135: 8)
  - Italian Earthquake benefit concert, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 135: 9)
  - Public relations material, 1984 (Box-folder 136: 1)
  - Contacts from the Republican National Convention, 1984 (Box-folder 136: 2)
  - Campaign Against Torture, 1984 (Box-folder 136: 3-6)
  - Printed matter, 1984 (Box-folder 136: 7)
  - Amnesty International board meeting, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 136: 8)
  - Photograph of GS at a lectern, 1981 (Box-folder 136: 9)
  - Clipping on the National Security Council, 1985 (Box-folder 136: 10)
  - Correspondence and printed matter, 1984 (Box-folder 136: 11)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1984
    - A (Box-folder 137: 1)
    - B (Box-folder 137: 2)
    - C (Box-folder 137: 3)
    - D (Box-folder 137: 4)
    - E (Box-folder 137: 5)
    - F (Box-folder 137: 6)
    - G (Box-folder 137: 7)
    - H (Box-folder 137: 8)
    - I-J (Box-folder 137: 9)
    - K (Box-folder 137: 10)
    - L (Box-folder 137: 11)
    - M (Box-folder 137: 12)
    - N (Box-folder 137: 13)
    - O (Box-folder 137: 14)
    - P (Box-folder 137: 15)
    - R (Box-folder 137: 16)
    - S (Box-folder 137: 17)
    - T (Box-folder 137: 18)
    - V (Box-folder 137: 19)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986
    - A (Box-folder 138: 1)
    - B (Box-folder 138: 2-3)
    - C (Box-folder 138: 4)
    - D (Box-folder 138: 5)
    - E (Box-folder 138: 6)
    - G (Box-folder 138: 7)
    - H (Box-folder 138: 8)
    - J (Box-folder 138: 9)
    - K (Box-folder 138: 10)
    - L (Box-folder 138: 11)
    - M (Box-folder 138: 12)
    - N (Box-folder 138: 13)
    - O (Box-folder 138: 14)
    - P (Box-folder 138: 15)
    - R (Box-folder 138: 16)
    - S (Box-folder 138: 17)
    - T (Box-folder 138: 18)
    - U (Box-folder 138: 19)
    - W (Box-folder 138: 20)
    - Y (Box-folder 138: 21)
  - Group adoption of Turkish student, 1985 (Box-folder 138: 22)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence, 1985
  - A (Box-folder 139: 1)
  - B (Box-folder 139: 2)
  - C (Box-folder 139: 3)
    Includes letter from Noam Chomsky on Cambodia
  - D (Box-folder 139: 4)
  - E (Box-folder 139: 5)
  - F (Box-folder 139: 6)
  - G (Box-folder 139: 7)
  - H (Box-folder 139: 8)
  - J (Box-folder 139: 9)
  - K (Box-folder 139: 10)
    Includes letter from Edward Kennedy
  - L (Box-folder 139: 11)
  - M (Box-folder 139: 12)
  - N (Box-folder 139: 13)
  - O (Box-folder 139: 14)
  - R (Box-folder 139: 15)
  - S (Box-folder 139: 16)
  - T (Box-folder 139: 17)
  - V (Box-folder 139: 18)
  - W-Z (Box-folder 139: 19)
- Photographs of GS and Leonard Sagan, 1986, 1992 (Box-folder 140: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1967, 1980-1985
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 140: 2)
  - Letter to Josip Broz Tito, 1967 (Box-folder 140: 3)
  - Article on GS from Sydsvenska dagbladet, 1980 (Box-folder 140: 4)
  - Donor lists, 1985 (Box-folder 140: 5)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence and printed matter, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 140: 6)
- Vietnam research materials, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 140: 7)
- Correspondence and working files, 1984-1992
  Includes materials from Amnesty International, the Aurora Foundation, and Humanitas
  - A (Box-folder 140: 8)
  - B (Box-folder 140: 9)
  - C (Box-folder 140: 10)
  - D (Box-folder 140: 11)
  - E-F (Box-folder 140: 12-13)
  - G (Box-folder 140: 14)
  - I-J (Box-folder 140: 15)
  - L-M (Box-folder 141: 1)
  - P (Box-folder 141: 2-4)
  - R (Box-folder 141: 5-6)
    Includes AI case sheet for Zbigniew Romaszewski
  - S (Box-folder 141: 7)
    Includes GS letters to Andrei Sakharov
  - U-V (Box-folder 142: 1-2)
  - W (Box-folder 142: 3)
  - X-Z (Box-folder 142: 4)
  - Unsorted correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 142: 5-7)
- Aurora Foundation, 1977-1993
  - Correspondence, 1977-1993
    - A (Box-folder 142: 8-9)
    - B (Box-folder 142: 10)
    - B (Box-folder 143: 1-2)
    - C (Box-folder 143: 3-6)
    - D (Box-folder 143: 7-11)
    - E (Box-folder 143: 12)
    - F (Box-folder 143: 13-16)
    - G (Box-folder 143: 17)
    - H (Box-folder 143: 18-19)
    - I-J (Box-folder 143: 20-23)
    - I-J (Box-folder 144: 1-2)
    - K (Box-folder 144: 3-6)
    - L (Box-folder 144: 7-11)
    - M (Box-folder 144: 12-15)
      Includes letter from Czesław Miłosz
    - N (Box-folder 144: 16)
    - O (Box-folder 144: 17)
    - P-Q (Box-folder 145: 1-2)
    - R (Box-folder 145: 3-4)
    - S (Box-folder 145: 5-8)
    - S (Box-folder 146: 1-2)
    - T (Box-folder 146: 3-7)
    - U-V (Box-folder 146: 8-11)
      Includes photographs of a 1986 meeting between GS, Joan Baez, and Armando Valladares
    - W (Box-folder 146: 12)
    - X-Z (Box-folder 146: 13)
  - Office files, 1987-1991
    - Abbasov, Janice, 1991 (Box-folder 146: 14)
    - Amnesty International correspondence and printed matter, 1990 (Box-folder 146: 15)
    - Baez, Joan, letter to GS, 1991 December 29 (Box-folder 146: 16)
    - Bennett, Ralph, 1991 (Box-folder 146: 17)
    - Board meeting, 1991 (Box-folder 146: 18)
    - Board members, 1991 (Box-folder 146: 19)
    - Board memoranda and clippings, 1991 (Box-folder 146: 20)
    - Brickner, Balfour, undated (Box-folder 146: 21)
      Report from Saigon
    - Cambodia Documentation Commission, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 1)
    - Denney, Stephen, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 2)
    - Personal correspondence received, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 147: 3)
    - Grant recipients, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 4)
    - Hong Kong, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 5)
    - Human rights, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 6-9)
    - Humanitas, undated (Box-folder 147: 10)
    - Israel, 1990 (Box-folder 147: 11)
    - Jackson, Karl and Jean, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 12)
    - Jones, Catherine Schlumberger, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 13)
    - K-L correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 147: 14-17)
    - M correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 147: 18-20)
    - Nagan, Winston P., 1991 (Box-folder 147: 21)
    - National Archives, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 22)
    - Notes under the Door, 1991 (Box-folder 147: 23)
    - P, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 147: 24)
    - Poland, 1990 (Box-folder 147: 25)
    - Prisoner questionnaire forms, undated (Box-folder 147: 26)
    - Programma voor Interdisciplinair Onderzoek naar Oorzaken van Mensenrechtenschendingen (PIOOM), 1990 (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - Questionnaires in French, undated (Box-folder 148: 2-3)
    - Reports sent, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 148: 4)
    - Romaszewski, Zbigniew, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 148: 5)
    - Schlumberger, Pierre, 1991 (Box-folder 148: 6)
    - South Africa, 1990 (Box-folder 148: 7-8)
    - T correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 148: 9-10)
    - Trong, Lucien, 1984 and undated (Box-folder 148: 11)
    - U-V file, 1990 and undated (Box-folder 148: 12)
- Photographic negatives of GS in Italy, 1980s (Box-folder 149: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1978-1989
  - "12-Point Program for the Prevention of Torture,", 1983 October (Box-folder 149: 2)
  - A-B correspondence, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 149: 3)
  - B-C correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 149: 4-5)
  - E-G, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 149: 6-7)
  - Bernstein, Shirley, 1987 (Box-folder 149: 8)
  - Board memorandum, 1986 December 1 (Box-folder 149: 9)
  - BBC Enterprises, 1985 (Box-folder 149: 10)
  - Cultural diversification task force meeting, 1986 (Box-folder 149: 11)
  - Wine labels, 1986 (Box-folder 149: 12)
  - Correspondence and internal documents, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 149: 13)
  - Eastern Europe Coordination Group, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 149: 14)
  - Group 19 internal documents, 1986 (Box-folder 149: 15)
  - G-K correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 150: 1)
  - Healy, John G. (Jack), 1986 (Box-folder 150: 2)
  - Henry, Charles, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 150: 3)
  - L-M correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 150: 4)
  - Lawyers Committee on Human Rights, 1985 (Box-folder 150: 5)
  - Map of southeast Asia, undated (Box-folder 150: 6)
  - N correspondence, 1987 (Box-folder 150: 7)
  - Nagy, Andras, 1981, 1986 (Box-folder 150: 8)
  - Neff, Monica, 1985 (Box-folder 150: 9)
  - Nicaragua, 1986 (Box-folder 150: 10)
  - Notes for party, undated (Box-folder 150: 11)
  - O-R correspondence, undated (Box-folder 150: 12)
  - Romaszewska, Agnieszka, 1987 (Box-folder 150: 13)
  - South Africa trip, 1989 (Box-folder 150: 14)
  - Wolf, Jiří, fundraiser, 1988 (Box-folder 150: 15-16)
  - Internal documents and correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 151: 1-2)
  - Group and leader list, 1989 March (Box-folder 151: 3)
  - 25th anniversary invitation lists, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 151: 4)
- Ronald Reagan remarks on GS, 1986 December 10 (Box-folder 151: 5)
- Knopf correspondence on book advance for GS's autobiography, 1986 (Box-folder 151: 6)
- GS Humanitas memorandum to Joan Baez, 1980 March (Box-folder 151: 7)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 151: 8)
- Aurora Foundation internal documents and correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 151: 9)
- Amnesty International internal documents, correspondence, and printed matter, 1976-1988 (Box-folder 152: 1)
- Aurora Foundation internal documents, correspondence, and printed matter, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 152: 2-4)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 152: 5-6)
- GS and Joan Baez letters to Lech Wałęsa, 1987 (Box-folder 152: 7)
- Leonard Sagan writings and correspondence, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 153: 1)
- Aurora Foundation correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 153: 2-6)
  Relates to award for Zbigniew Romaszewski
- Biographical file on GS's car accident in Poland, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 153: 7)
- Institute for Research on Women and Gender, Stanford University, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 153: 8)
- Printed matter, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 153: 9)
- Amnesty International, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 153: 10)
- Aurora Foundation award ceremony for Zbigniew Romaszewski, 1987 (Box 154)
  Includes correspondence, clippings, and photographs of GS, Czesław Miłosz, and others at Stanford Memorial Church
- Joan Baez cartoon depicting office work, undated (Box-folder 155: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1985-1993
  - Calendar, 1993 (Box-folder 155: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box-folder 155: 3)
  - Donors, 1988 (Box-folder 155: 4)
  - Fundraising, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 155: 5)
- Aurora Foundation, 1987-1992
  - Correspondence and internal documents, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 155: 6-8)
    Includes report by GS on her trip to Poland
  - Award for Aung San Suu Kyi, 1991 (Box-folder 155: 9)
- Karl Jackson (National Security Council) letter to GS, 1990 (Box-folder 155: 10)
- "Stanford Program," audiocassette, 1991 November 9 (Box-folder 155: 11)
- Amnesty International correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 156)
  Accordion file
- South Africa file, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 157: 1-8)
  Includes trip report
- Leonard Sagan file, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 157: 9)
  Mainly letters received regarding Chile
- Los Angeles Times editorial by GS, 1988 May 5 (Box-folder 157: 10)
  On the U.N. torture treaty
- Printed matter, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 157: 11)
  Mainly Amnesty International publications
- Personal letters received, 1945, 1981 (Box-folder 157: 12)
  Includes English translation of letter from Tiberio Panzini
- Amnesty International, 1983-1993
  - Internal documents and correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 157: 13-15)
  - Film treatment for the Campaign Against Torture, 1983 (Box-folder 157: 16)
- Vietnam research materials, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 158: 1)
- Amnesty International, 1978-1993
  - Annual general meeting, 1987 (Box-folder 158: 2)
  - Western Regional Conference, 1993 (Box-folder 158: 3)
  - Correspondence and printed matter, 1978-1992 (Box-folder 158: 4)
  - Inventory of research materials, undated (Box-folder 158: 5)
  - Angola, 1989 (Box-folder 158: 6)
  - Bulgaria, China, Cuba, and Czechoslovakia clippings, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 158: 7)
  - Foreign affairs, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 158: 8)
  - Guyana, Haiti, and Hong Kong, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 158: 9)
  - International PEN, 1988 (Box-folder 158: 10)
  - South Africa, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 158: 11)
  - South Africa and Poland, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 158: 12)
- Aurora Foundation, 1973-1993
  - Letters received regarding Reader's Digest article, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 159: 1-2)
  - Vietnam correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 159: 3)
  - Vietnam research materials, 1992 (Box-folder 159: 4)
- Amnesty International, 1973-1993
  - Internal documents, notes, and correspondence, 1973 (Box-folder 159: 5-6)
  - Letters received, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 159: 7)
  - Printed matter and clippings, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 159: 8)
- Exhibit material, undated (Box-folder 160: 1)
  Depicts the "corragio" incident from GS's experiences during World War II
- Invitations received by GS, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 160: 2)
- Amnesty International, 1990-1991
  - 20th anniversary event, 1991 (Box-folder 160: 3-4)
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1990 (Box-folder 160: 5)
- "Open Letter to the Socialist Republic of Vietnam," by Joan Baez, Los Angeles Times, 1979 May 30 (Box-folder 160: 6)
- Aurora Foundation, 1985-1992
  - Research material and correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 160: 7-10)
    Mainly on Vietnam
  - Writings and notes by GS, undated (Box-folder 160: 11)
  - Cambodia, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 160: 12)
  - Letters received, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 161: 1)
    Letters in Spanish in response to the Reader's Digest article on GS
  - International Society for Human Rights grant proposal, 1991 (Box-folder 161: 2)
  - Vietnamese press on GS and the Aurora Foundation, 1991 (Box-folder 161: 3)
  - Correspondence and research material, 1991 (Box-folder 161: 4)
  - Letters received, 1992 (Box-folder 161: 5)
- Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 161: 6)
- Amnesty International Group 19 correspondence and internal documents, 1974-1992 (Box-folder 161: 7)
- GS speech in Los Altos, CA, 1992 April 15 (Box-folder 161: 8)
  Photograph and program
- GS statement at the Jefferson Awards, 1987 June 24 (Box-folder 161: 9)
- GS notes on Vietnam, 1980s (Box-folder 161: 10)
- Biographical clipping on GS from The San Jose Mercury News, 1979 January 1 (Box-folder 161: 11)
- Human rights printed matter, 1993 (Box-folder 162: 1)
- Vietnam research materials, 1973, 1992
  - Doan Viet Hoat, 1992 (Box-folder 162: 2)
  - "Inside a Vietnamese Prison Now,", 1973 March 14 (Box-folder 162: 3)
- Poland clippings and correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 162: 4-5)
- Letters received, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 162: 6)
  Includes letter of congratulations from Ronald Reagan
- Torture and human rights printed matter, 1987-1992 (Box-folder 162: 7-8)
- Vietnam research materials, 1980-1992
  - Printed matter, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 162: 9)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 162: 10)
  - Printed matter, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 163: 1)
  - The Smaller Dragon Under Torture, by Tran Phu Loc, typescript, 1980 (Box-folder 163: 2)
  - My 1632 Days of "Reeducation:" An Account of Life in Six Reeducation Camps in Vietnam, 1975-1979, by Tran Tri Vu, typescript, circa 1984 (Box-folder 163: 3)
  - Lost Years: My 1632 Days in Vietnamese Reeducation Camps, published copy, 1988 (Box-folder 164: 1)
- Proposal for a human rights education program in Poland and Czechoslovakia, 1992 (Box-folder 164: 2)
- Vietnamese émigré newspapers, 1993 (Box-folder 164: 3)
- Human rights printed matter, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 164: 4)
- Letter to GS regarding Greek prisoners of conscience, 1976 January 27 (Box-folder 164: 5)
- Declassified report on German concentration camps compiled by the British, photocopy from the U.S. National Archives, 1944 August (Box-folder 164: 6)
- Clippings and printed matter related to Amnesty International, 1975-1992 (Box-folder 164: 7)
- Human rights printed matter and clippings, 1987-1993 (Box 165)
- Human rights clippings, 1990 (Box-folder 166: 1-2)
- Aurora Foundation, 1991-1993
  - Fundraising correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 166: 3)
  - List of religious prisoners, 1992 February 27 (Box-folder 166: 4)
  - Report from GS's trip to Paris, 1992 October 2 (Box-folder 166: 5)
  - Finances, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 166: 6-14)
- Guido Bustelli letter and poem to GS, 1991 June 7 (Box-folder 166: 15)
- GS letter to Another Mother for Peace, 1970 February 9 (Box-folder 166: 16)
- Boat people, 1991 (Box-folder 166: 17)
- Report on LS's visit to Poland, 1990 April 18 (Box-folder 166: 18)
- Charlotte Beyers correspondence, 1990 (Box-folder 166: 19)
- Photographs of GS with Ian Martin, Joan Baez, and Lydia Ghielmetti, 1992 (Box-folder 167: 1)
- Aurora Foundation, 1989-1993
  - Fundraising, 1990 (Box-folder 167: 2-4)
  - Schedule for trip to Washington, DC, 1992 March-April (Box-folder 167: 5)
  - Nguyen Dan Que appeal, 1992 (Box-folder 167: 6)
  - Routine correspondence and address lists, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 167: 7-15)
  - Christine Sadowski correspondence, 1989 (Box-folder 167: 16)
  - Media relations, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 167: 17)
  - Book review of Violations of Human Rights in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, 1989 (Box-folder 167: 18)
  - Bills for secretarial work, 1993 (Box-folder 167: 19-21)
- Amnesty International, 1974, 1992-1993
  - Routine correspondence and address lists, 1992 (Box-folder 167: 22-24)
    Includes thank you letter to Ronald Reagan
  - John G. Healey correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 167: 25-31)
  - Matchbox, vol. 1, no. 1, 1974 (Box-folder 167: 32)
- Biographical file, 1984-1989
  - Transcript of interview with GS on the end of World War II, her nightmares, and Amnesty International, 1989 April-May (Box-folder 167: 33)
  - San Francisco Chronicle column on GS's accident in Poland, 1987 December 3 (Box-folder 167: 34)
  - New York Times clipping, 1984 April 15 (Box-folder 167: 35)
  - Photograph of GS after accident in Poland, 1987 October (Box-folder 167: 36)
- Ricordi della resistenza italiana, 1943-1945, by Guido Bustelli, 1966 (Box-folder 168: 1)
- Rose Styron curriculum vitae, 1992 December (Box-folder 168: 2)
- Amnesty International report on India, 1992 (Box-folder 168: 3)
- Datebook kept during trips to Paris and Rome, photocopy, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 168: 4)
- GS letter to Charles Palm describing a meeting with Hanoi's ambassador to France in 1968, 1992 October 7 (Box-folder 168: 5)
- Aurora Foundation, 1985-1992
  - Board members list, 1990 September 15 (Box-folder 168: 6)
  - Mandate, 1992 March 28 (Box-folder 168: 7)
  - Bills for secretarial work, 1992 (Box-folder 168: 8)
  - Correspondence on Vietnam, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 168: 9)
  - Routine correspondence, 1992 (Box-folder 168: 10-11)
  - Vietnam, 1992 (Box-folder 168: 12-17)